A Guide to the Collie Burton Papers, 1965-1977
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
Collie Burton Papers, 1965-1977
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 267
4 linear feet
Collie Burton
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for use without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated to the Department by Mr. Burton in February 1990.
Biographical/Historical Information
Mr. Burton has been educated in Virginia, Pennsylvania and Ohio and has held numerous civic positions in Richmond.
Scope and Content Information
The collection includes articles, correspondence and publications on various issues. The bulk of the material details the lawsuits against the FCC and Richmond area radio and television stations initiated by the Black Broadcasting Coalition (BBC) in the early 1970s.
Arrangement
Arrangement
Materials arranged in alphabetical order and chronologically therein.
Organization
Most of the files were not in any order and arrangement and order was imposed by the Department to aid research.
Series I--Alphabetical Files (n.d., 1971-1977)
Series II--Black Broadcasting Coalition (BBC) vs. Federal Communications Commission (FCC) (n.d., 1966-1976)
Series III--Oversize (n.d.)
Contents List
- Alphabetical files, n.d., 1971-1977
  - Airlie Institute: Examining a Statistician 1973 (Box-folder 1.1)
  - Airlie Institute: Planned Civil Disabilities Litigation 1973 (Box-folder 1.2)
  - Airlie Institute: Use of Arrest and Conviction Records 1973 (Box-folder 1.3)
  - Briggs vs. Brown and Williams Tobacco Company 1976 (Box-folder 1.4)
  - Bilingual Bicultural Coalition on Mass Media, Inc. vs FCC etc. 1977 (Box-folder 1.5)
  - Community Problems 1972 (Box-folder 1.6)
  - Conference on Media Relations 1971 (Box-folder 1.7)
  - Proposal to HUD--Comprehensive Counseling Grant, n.d. (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Virginia State College, n.d., 1972-1973 (Box-folder 1.9)
  - Voter Registration, n.d. (Box-folder 1.10)
- BBC vs. FCC, n.d., 1966-1976
  - Affirmative Action 1972-1976 (Box-folder 1.11)
  - Alabama Educational Television Commission 1975 (Box-folder 2.1)
  - AM Station Assignment Standards 1975 (Box-folder 2.2)
  - Articles, n.d., 1973 (Box-folder 2.3)
  - Broadcast Station License Expiration Periods 1972 (Box-folder 2.4)
  - Citizens Communication Center, n.d. (Box-folder 2.5)
  - Correspondence 1974-1976 (Box-folder 2.6)
  - Employment 1972 (Box-folder 2.7)
  - Employment Discrimination Litigation against the Federal Government 1973 (Box-folder 2.8)
  - Evening Star Broadcasting Company 1972 (Box-folder 2.9)
  - FCC News 1975 (Box-folder 2.10)
  - For 395 WANT, WVEC, WBBL 1972 (Box-folder 2.11)
  - Guide to Citizen Action in Radio and Television 1971 (Box-folder 2.12)
  - Hubbard Broadcasting, Inc. 1976 (Box-folder 2.13)
  - JOBS 1972 (Box-folder 2.14)
  - Johnson Motor Lines 1972 (Box-folder 2.15)
  - Joint Appendix--WTVR Folder 1 of 3 (Box-folder 2.16)
  - Joint Appendix--WTVR Folder 2 of 3 (Box-folder 3.1)
  - Joint Appendix--WTVR Folder 3 of 3 (Box-folder 3.2)
  - Leflore Broadcasting (WSWG-AM_ and Dixie Broadcasting (WSWG-FM) 1975 (Box-folder 3.3)
  - Metromedia (WTTG-TV) 1972 (Box-folder 3.4)
  - Metromedia Petition to Deny (Box-folder 3.5)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d., 1971-1972 (Box-folder 3.6)
  - National Black Media Coalition 1975 (Box-folder 3.7)
  - Petition to Prevent Continued Violations 1972 (Box-folder 4.1)
  - Publications (Box-folder 4.2)
  - Question of Determination of Back Pay in Equal Employment Cases, n.d. (Box-folder 5.1)
  - Questionaire to Evaluate Impact of Public on Broadcasting, n.d. (Box-folder 5.2)
  - Reply to Petition to Prevent Continued Violations (Box-folder 5.3)
  - Research file (Box-folder 5.4)
  - Research file (Box-folder 5.5)
  - Research--United Church of Christ vs FCC 1966, 1969 (Box-folder 5.6)
  - Research file II (A) 75-255 (Box-folder 5.7)
  - Sample Petition to Deny, n.d. (Box-folder 6.1)
  - Saint Regis Paper Company, n.d. (Box-folder 6.2)
  - Scripps Howard Broadcasting Company (WWMC-TV), n.d. (Box-folder 6.3)
  - Suits Against the Federal Government for Employment Discrimination 1973 (Box-folder 6.4)
  - Virginia Medical Information System (Grant), n.d. (Box-folder 6.5)
  - Virginia Schools, n.d. (Box-folder 6.6)
  - WCFL Brief (partial), n.d. (Box-folder 6.7)
  - WEZS 1965, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 6.8)
  - WHEC--Petition for Reconsideration 1975 (Box-folder 6.9)
  - WIIN 1970 (Box-folder 6.10)
  - WIKI, WDYL 1972 (Box-folder 6.11)
  - WJAS 1972 (Box-folder 6.12)
  - WRGM 1972 (Box-folder 6.13)
  - WRNL, WRXL 1972 (Box-folder 6.14)
  - WRVA, WRVQ 1972 (Box-folder 6.15)
  - WRVA, WRVQ, n.d., 1972-1973 (Box-folder 6.16)
  - WTVR Folder 1 of 6, n.d., 1967-1972 (Box-folder 7.1)
  - WTVR Folder 2 of 6 1972 (Box-folder 7.2)
  - WTVR Folder 3 of 6 1972 (Box-folder 7.3)
  - WTVR Folder 4 of 6 1973-1975 (Box-folder 7.4)
  - WTVR Folder 5 of 6 1975 (Box-folder 8.1)
  - WTVR Folder 6 of 6 1976-1977 (Box-folder 8.2)
  - WVOK 1975 (Box-folder 8.3)
  - WWBT-TV 1972-1973 (Box-folder 8.4)
  - WXEX-TV, WLEE, n.d., 1972 (Box-folder 8.5)
  - WXGI, WIVE 1971-1973, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 8.6)
- Oversize, n.d.
  - Poster of programs (Oversize 25)